怎么回事 出什么事了
So what is it? What's wrong?
我不知道
I don't know.
某种信号把塔迪斯引离了航线
Some kind of signal, drawing the TARDIS off course.
我们在哪里 -地球 犹他州 北美
Where are we? - Earth. Utah, North America.
大约地下八百米
About half a mile underground.
我们在什么时间
And...when are we?
2012年
2012.
那离现在很近啊 我这时候应该26岁
God, that's so close. I should be 26!
天呐 像是一个巨大的博物馆
Blimey. Like a great big museum.
一个外星人博物馆
An alien museum.
看来是个爱好者
Someone's got a hobby
他们肯定在这上面花了大钱
they must've spent a fortune on this.
勾起了不少回忆啊 月球尘埃
Chunks of meteorite. Moondust.
那是罗斯威尔太空船的里程表
That's the mileometer from the Roswell spaceship.
那个是斯利辛 斯利辛的胳膊
That's a bit of Slitheen! That's a Slitheen's arm -
被做成了填充标本
it's been stuffed!
瞧瞧你
Ah, look at you!
这是什么
What is it?
我的一个老朋友
An old friend of mine.
其实是敌人
Well, enemy.
噩梦般的存在 沦落成一个展品
The stuff of nightmares, reduced to an exhibit.
人老了就爱伤感 -是它发的信号吗
I'm getting old. - Is that where the signal's coming from?
不 它已经死透了 信号是活的
Nah, it's stone dead. The signal's alive.
有什么东西在呼唤
Something's reaching out.
发求救信号
Calling for help.
如果有人在收藏外星人
If someone's collecting aliens,
你可是头号展品
that makes you Exhibit A.
神秘博士第一季第六集
戴立克
全体注意
Attention all personnel.
恶狼一号正在降落 恶狼一号正在降落
Bad Wolf 1 descending, Bad Wolf 1 descending.
我谨代表我们全体
On behalf of all of us,
祝您生日快乐 先生
I wanna wish you a very happy birthday, sir.
总统先生向你转达他个人的祝福
The President conveys his personal best wishes.
总统的支持率下降了十点 我要换掉他
The President is 10 points down. I want him replaced.
我不认为这很明智 先生
I don't think that's wise, sir.
多谢你的意见 你被解雇了 处理掉他
Thank you so much for your opinion. You're fired. Get rid of him.
清除他的记忆 把他扔到随便哪的路边
Wipe his memory and put him on the road someplace.
孟菲斯 明尼阿波利斯
Memphis, Minneapolis -
随便哪个M开头的地方
somewhere beginning with M.
关于下一任总统 你有什么想法
So, the next President, what d'you think?
共和党还是民主党
Republican or Democrat?
民主党 先生 -为什么
Democrat, sir. - For what reason?
他们更有趣 先生
They're just so funny, sir?
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
戈达德 先生 戴安娜·戈达德
Goddard, sir. Diana Goddard.
我喜欢你 戴安娜·戈达德
I like you, Diana Goddard.
那个英国小孩呢 -先生 先生
So where's the English kid? - Sir, sir!
我又买到十件藏品 范·斯塔邓先生
I bought ten more artefacts, Mr Van Statten.
拿过来给我看看
Bring them on. Let me see 'em.
不好意思先生 还有一件更紧急的事情
Sir, with respect, there's something more urgent.
我们在地下53层抓住了两个闯入者
We arrested two intruders 53 floors down.
我们不知道他们是怎么进来的
We don't know how they got in.
我告诉你他们怎么进来的 从窗户进来的
I'll tell you how they got in -- in-tru-da window!
谐音"入侵者" 多好笑啊
In-tru-da window, that was funny!
把他们带过来让我们看看
Bring them in. Let's see them.
另外告诉西蒙斯我想看我的小宠物 快去
And tell Simmons I want to visit my little pet. Get to it.
西蒙斯 你最好给我些好消息
Simmons, you'd better give me good news!
它说话了吗
Is it talking?
不算说话 不
Not exactly talking, no.
那它在干什么 -惨叫
Then what's it doing? - Screaming.
可以吗
Is that any good?
这是最后一件
And this is the last.
花了八十万美元 -它是干什么的
Paid $800, 000 for it. - What does it do?
您看到边上的管子了吗
Well, you see the tubes on the side?
应该是传输什么的通道 我想可能是燃料
Must be to channel something, I think maybe fuel.
我可不推荐这样拿着 -闭嘴
I really wouldn't hold it like that. - Shut it!
真的 你拿错了
Really though, that's wrong.
有什么危险吗
Is it dangerous?
没有 只是看起来很傻
No, it just looks silly.
你只是需要…
You just need to be...
温柔一点
delicate.
这是件乐器
It's a musical instrument.
它离家可真够远的
And it's a long way from home.
让我试试
Here, let me.
我说了要温柔
I did say delicate.
它能响应最微弱的触碰
It reacts to the smallest fingerprint.
它很精确
It needs precision.
非常好 很专业的样子
Very good. Quite the expert.
你不也是吗
As are you.
你到底是谁
Who exactly are you?
我是博士 你是谁
I'm the Doctor. And who are you?
说的好像你不知道似的
Like you don't know.
我们收藏了全世界
We're hidden away with the most valuable collection
最有价值的外星藏品
of extraterrestrial artefacts in the world,
而你居然一不小心就闯进来了
and you just stumbled in by mistake.
基本就是这样
Pretty much sums me up, yeah.
问题是 你是怎么进来的
Question is, how did you get in?
地下53层 带着你可爱的共犯
53 floors down, with your little cat-burglar accomplice.
你也是个不错的收藏家 她挺漂亮的
Quite a collector yourself - she's rather pretty.
你再这么叫她 她可就要扇你了
She's gonna smack you if you keep calling her "She".
她也是个英国人
She's English, too!
方特罗伊小爵爷 给你找了个女朋友
Hey, Little Lord Fauntleroy, got you a girlfriend.
这位是亨利·范·斯塔邓
This is Mr Henry van Statten.
他平时又是什么身份
And who's he when he's at home?
亨利·范·斯塔邓先生拥有整个互联网
Mr Van Statten owns the internet.
别犯傻了 没人能拥有互联网
Don't be stupid. No-one owns the internet.
就让全世界继续这么认为吧 孩子
Let's just keep the world thinking that, right, kids?
所以你精通很多东西
So you're an expert in everything,
除了你博物馆里的东西
except the things in your museum.
你不懂的东西 就锁起来
What you don't understand, you lock up.
你号称你的知识更丰富 -不用号称
And you claim greater knowledge? - I don't need somebody claims.
我知道我有多棒
I know how good I am.
可我却在"笼子"旁抓住了你
Yet I captured you right next to the Cage.
你们在下面干什么
What were you doing down there?
你觉得呢
You tell me.
笼子里关着我唯一的活标本
The Cage contains my one living specimen.
是什么 -说得好像你不知道似的
What's that? - Like you don't know.
带我去看 -你想看吗
Show me. - You wanna see it?
老天 我都能闻到火药味了
Blimey, you can smell the testosterone.
戈达德 通知笼子我们马上下去
Goddard! Inform the Cage we're heading down.
你 英国小伙 看着那个姑娘
You, English, look after the girl.
去干你们英国佬那些卿卿我我的事去吧
Go and canoodle or spoon or whatever it is you British do.
而你 没有名字的博士
And you, Doctor with no name.
来看看我的小宠物
Come and see my pet!
我们什么办法都试过了
We've tried everything.
这生物把自己关得严严实实
The creature has shielded itself,
但里面确实有生命迹象
but there's definite signs of life inside.
里面 什么的里面 -欢迎回来先生
Inside? Inside what? - Welcome back, sir!
我不得不关闭电力
I've had to take the power down -
铁罐头正在休息 -铁罐头
the Metaltron is resting. - Metaltron?
我起的 挺不错吧
Thought of it myself. Good, isn't it?
不过我还是更希望知道它真正的名字
Although I'd much prefer to find out its real name.
给 你最好戴上这个
Here, you'd better put these on.
上一个碰它的伙计
The last guy that touched it...
已经灰飞烟灭了
burst into flames.
我不会碰它的
I won't touch it, then.
去吧 博士
Go ahead, Doctor.
让我见识一下
Impress me.
得到结果之前不要开门
Don't open that door until we get a result.
听着 我对你的遭遇表示抱歉
Look, I'm sorry about this,
范·斯塔邓先生自以为聪明 不用理他
Mr. Van Statten might think he's clever, but never mind him.
我是来帮你的 我是博士
I've come to help. I'm the Doctor.
博…士…
Doc...tor...
这不可能
Impossible!
是那个博士吗
THE Doctor?
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
让我出去 -消灭
Let me out! - EXTERMINATE!
先生 它会杀了他的 -它说话了
Sir, it's going to kill him! - It's talking!
你是戴立克的敌人
You are an enemy of the Daleks.
你必须被毁灭
You must be destroyed!
坏掉了
It's not working.
妙极了
Fantastic!
简直妙极了
Oh, fantastic!
如此无力 看看你
Powerless. Look at you.
伟大的太空垃圾 感觉怎么样
The great space dustbin. How does it feel?
后退 -为什么要后退
Keep back! - What for?
你能把我怎么样
What are you gonna do to me?
如果你不能杀人了
If you can't kill,
那还会干什么 戴立克
then what are you good for, Dalek?
你的存在还有什么意义
What's the point of you?
你什么都不是
You're nothing.
你在这里干什么
What the hell are you here for?
我在…等待命令
I am...waiting for orders.
这是什么意思 -我是一名士兵
What does that mean? - I am a soldier.
服从命令是我的天职
I was born to receive orders.
可你得不到命令了 永远都得不到了
Well, you're never gonna get any. Not ever.
我要求得到命令
I demand orders!
再也不会有命令了
They're never gonna come.
你的种族已经死了 全死光了
Your race is dead. You all burnt.
你们所有人 一千万艘飞船
All of you. Ten million ships on fire.
整个戴立克种族一瞬间全毁灭了
The entire Dalek race wiped out, in one second.
你撒谎
You lie!
是我亲眼看到的 是我亲手造成的
I watched it happen. I made it happen.
你毁灭了我们
You destroyed us?
我别无选择
I had no choice.
那时间领主们呢
And what of the Time Lords?
死了
Dead.
和你们同归于尽了
They burnt with you.
最后一次时间大战终结了
The end of the last great Time War.
所有人都输了
Everyone lost.
只有懦夫幸存了下来
And the coward survived.
我接到了你的小信号了
Oh, and I caught your little signal.
"救救我" 可怜的小东西
"Help me." Poor little thing.
但是没有人会来了 因为只剩你了
But there's no-one else coming cos there's no-one else left.
全宇宙只剩下我一个
I am alone in the universe.
是的
Yep.
你也是
So are you.
我们是一样的
We are the same.
我们不一样 我不是…
We're not the same! I'm not...
不 等等
No, wait.
也许是的
Maybe we are.
你说得对 你说得有道理
You're right! Yeah, Ok! You've got a point.
我知道该怎么办了
Cos I know what to do.
我知道应该干什么了
I know what should happen.
我知道你应得的下场了
I know what you deserve.
消灭
Exterminate.
请怜悯我
Have pity!
凭什么 你们从来没有怜悯过
Why should I? You never did!
把他弄出去
Get him out!
救命
Help me!
我救了你的命 跟我说话啊
I saved your life. Now talk to me.
该死的 跟我说话
Godammit, talk to me!
你必须毁了它
You've got to destroy it!
全宇宙最后一只
The last in the universe.
我还知道你的名字
And now I know your name.
戴立克
Da-lek.
跟我说话 戴立克
Speak to me, Dalek!
我是亨利·范·斯塔邓 你看清楚
I am Henry Van Statten - now recognise me!
让它再开口说话 西蒙斯
Make it talk again, Simmons.
不惜一切代价
Whatever it takes.
不好意思有点乱
Sorry about the mess.
范·斯塔邓先生就放任我自由活动
Mr. Van Statten sort of lets me do my own thing,
只要我能按时交货就行
so long as I deliver the goods.
你觉得那是什么东西
What do you think that is?
金属碎片吗 -没错
A lump of metal? - Yeah.
可是我觉得 我几乎能肯定
Yeah, but I think... Well, I'm almost certain,
这是宇宙飞船船体的一部分
it's from the hull of a spacecraft.
问题在于 这些都是真的
The thing is, it's all true,
这些联合国试图隐瞒的事情
everything the United Nations tries to keep quiet.
宇宙飞船啊 外星人啊 天外来客啊
Spacecraft, aliens, visitors to Earth.
他们真的存在
They really exist.
太惊人了 -我知道听起来难以置信
That's amazing. - I know it sounds incredible.
但是我真的相信
But I honestly believe
宇宙中到处都有生命的存在
the whole universe is just teeming with life.
我真是大开眼界
I'm gobsmacked, yeah.
你是干什么的呢 坐这给它们分类吗
And you do what? Sit here and catalogue it?
这是世上最棒的工作
Best job in the world!
想象一下你要是能走出这个地方
Imagine if you could get out there.
去星球间旅行一番 亲眼见识见识
Travel amongst the stars and see it for real.
我愿意为此付出一切 不过我觉得这不可能
Yeah. I'd give anything. I don't think it's ever gonna happen.
至少咱们的有生之年不可能 -世事难料
Not in our lifetimes. - Oh, you never know.
那些声称自己进过宇宙飞船
What about all those people who say they've
跟外星人说过话的人呢
been inside of spaceships and things, and talked to aliens?
我觉得他们是疯子 -我也觉得
I think they're nutters. - Yeah. Me too.
那你是怎么来到这里的
So how d'you end up here?
范·斯塔邓在全球各地都有雇员
Van Statten has agents all over the world,
招募世上各种天才
looking for geniuses to recruit.
对哦 你是天才
Oh, right, you're a genius.
抱歉 但…没错 我也没办法
Sorry, but...Yeah. I can't help it
我天生就很聪明
I was born clever.
我八岁时 登入了美国的防御系统
When I was eight, I logged onto the US defence system.
差点引起第三次世界大战
Nearly caused World War Three.
那是件很有趣的事吗
What, and that's funny, is it?
你真应该亲眼瞧瞧
You should've been there.
看他们跑来跑去 真是妙极了
Just to see them running about. Fantastic!
你说话很像博士
You sound like the Doctor.
你和他… -不 我们只是朋友
Are you and him... ? - No, we're just friends.
很好
Good.
为什么好啊
Why's that good?
就是很好
Just is.
那你难道不想下楼看看吗
So, wouldn't you rather be downstairs?
你这里都是一些金属东西
You've got these bits of metal and stuff,
但是范·斯塔邓先生手上有个活生生的家伙
but Mr Van Statten's got a living creature down there.
我问过他 但是他不给别人看
Yeah. Well, I did ask, but he keeps it to himself.
不过话说回来 如果是个天才
Although... if you're a genius,
要想突破通讯系统也不是什么难事
it doesn't take long to patch through on the comms system.
那我们就去看看吧
Let's have a look then!
它没什么动静 那个外星人
It doesn't do much, the alien.
它很奇怪 有点…没用
It's weird, it's kind of...useless.
像个巨大的胡椒罐
It's just like this great big pepperpot.
他们在折磨它 博士呢 -我不知道
It's being tortured. Where's the Doctor? - I don't know.
带我下去 快点
Take me down there. Now.
那些金属只是盔甲
The metal's just battle armour.
真正的戴立克躲在里面
The real Dalek creature is inside.
它长什么样 -如同噩梦
What does it look like? - A nightmare.
是一种变异体
It's a mutation.
它们的基因被改造了
They were genetically engineered.
移除了它们所有的情绪 除了憎恨
Every single emotion was removed, except hate.
基因改造 谁干的
Genetically engineered? By whom?
他是一个天才 范·斯塔邓
By a genius, Van Statten.
在自己的小世界里称王称霸 你肯定喜欢他
By a man who was king of his own little world. You'd like him.
它已经在地球上存在了五十多年了
It's been on Earth for over 50 years.
在各种私人拍卖会上出售
Sold at private auction,
在各个收藏家手中几经易手
moving from one collection to another.
为什么现在会变成一个大威胁了呢
Why would it be a threat now?
因为我来了 它怎么到地球上的 谁知道
Because I'm here. How did it get to Earth? Does anyone know?
记录显示它像陨石一样在空中出现
The records say it came from the sky like a meteorite.
坠落在阿森松群岛上
It fell to Earth on the Ascension Islands,
在陷坑里燃烧了三天
burnt in its crater for three days
然后才有人能接近它
before anybody could get near it.
那三天里它一直在尖叫 肯定已经疯了
And all that time, it was screaming. Must have gone insane.
肯定是穿越了时间到这里来的
It must have fallen through time.
唯一的幸存者 -你是说某场战争的吗
The only survivor. - You talked about a war?
时间大战 我的族人与戴立克的最后一战
The Time War. The final battle between my people and the Daleks.
但你也活下来了 -不是我能选择的
But you survived too. - Not by choice.
也就是说戴立克
This means the Dalek
不是地球上唯一的外星人 博士
isn't the only alien on Earth, Doctor.
还有你 你的种族中仅存的一名
There's you. The only one of your kind in existence.
现在…笑一个
Now...Smile!
两颗心脏 双血管系统
Two hearts. A binary vascular system!
我一定能申请个专利 -这就是你的秘密
Oh, I am so gonna patent this. - So that's your secret.
你不仅搞收藏 还从中寻找利益
You don't just collect stuff, you scavenge it.
这种技术已经来到地球几个世纪了
This technology has been falling to Earth for centuries.
只需要让合适的人恰当利用就好了
All it took was the right mind to use it properly.
我从外星垃圾中捡到的好处
Oh, the advances I've made from alien junk -
你绝对想不到 博士
you have no idea, Doctor!
宽带就是受到了罗斯威尔事件的启发
Broadband? Roswell.
去年 我的科学家培养了俄罗斯陨石坑
Just last year, my scientists cultivated bacteria
中的细菌 你猜我们发现了什么
from the Russian Crater, and do you know what we found?
根治感冒的药物
The cure for the common cold.
不过一直藏在实验室里
Kept it within the laboratory,
当然没必要让大家为之兴奋 对吧
of course. No need to get people excited.
我能卖这么多治标的药 何必还要治本呢
Why sell one cure when I can sell a thousand palliatives?
你知道戴立克是什么样的吗 范·斯塔邓
Do you know what a Dalek is, van Statten?
戴立克至少不虚伪
A Dalek is honest.
他生来只为一件事 种族的存活
It does what it was born to do, for the survival of its species.
你地牢里的那个生物人品都比你好
That creature in your dungeon is better than you.
既然如此 我也要遵从我的本心
In that case, I will be true to myself.
继续前进
And continue.
听我说 楼下那个东西
Listen to me! That thing downstairs
会把我们全部杀光
is gonna kill every last one of us!
谁都逃不出那个笼子
Nothing can escape the Cage.
但它觉醒了 它知道我在这儿 它会出来的
But it's woken up! It knows I'm here! It's gonna get out!
范·斯塔邓 我发誓
Van Statten, I swear,
这基地里没有一个人是安全的
no-one on this base is safe.
整个星球都不安全
No-one on this planet!
站住别动 -三级安全许可
Hold it right there. - Level three access.
范·斯塔邓先生授予的特殊权限
Special clearance from Mr. Van Statten.
别靠得太近
Don't get too close.
你好
Hello?
你疼吗
Are you in pain?
我叫洛斯·泰勒 我有个朋友能帮你
My name's Rose Tyler. I've got a friend who can help.
他叫博士
He's called the Doctor.
你叫什么
What's your name?
是的
Yes.
什么
What?
我很痛苦
I am in pain.
他们折磨我
They torture me,
但他们仍然很怕我
but still they fear me.
你怕我吗
Do you fear me?
不
No.
我快死了
I am dying.
不 我们能帮你
No, we can help.
我不怕死
I welcome death.
但我很高兴
But I am glad
临死之前
that before I die,
终于遇见了一个
I met a human
不怕我的人类
who was not afraid.
我能帮什么忙吗
Isn't there anything I can do?
我的种族灭绝了
My race is dead.
我也会孤独地死去
I shall die alone.
洛斯 不
Rose, no!
推算基因物质
Genetic material extrapolated.
启动细胞重建
Initiate cellular reconstruction!
你干了什么
What the hell have you done?
你准备干什么 把我吸死吗
What are you gonna do? Sucker me to death?
他快死了 做点什么吧 -红色警报
It's killing him! Do something! - Condition red.
重复 这不是演习
'Repeat, this is not a drill!'
如果你想活命就把我放了
Release me if you want to live.
你得把他关在牢里 -博士 是我的错
You've got to keep it in that cell! - Doctor, it's all my fault.
我已经封锁了牢房 它出不来的
I've sealed the compartment. It can't get out.
那个锁有数十亿种组合
The lock's got a billion combinations.
戴立克是天才 它能在一秒钟内
A Dalek is a genius. It can calculate
进行数万亿次的计算
a thousand billion combinations in one second flat.
开火
Open fire!
别开枪 我不想伤害到它
Don't shoot it - I want it unharmed!
洛斯 快出来
Rose, get out of there!
迪马乔 把这两个平民活着带出去
De Maggio, get the civilians out alive.
这是命令 明白吗
That is your job, got that?
你们  跟我来
You! With me!
笼子已失守 先生
Abandoning the Cage, sir!
我们在失去电力 它快把基地的电力吸干了
We're losing power. It's draining the base.
天呐
Oh, my God.
它正在吸收整个犹他州的电力
It's draining the entire power supplies of the whole of Utah.
它在下载 -下载什么
It's downloading. - Downloading what?
先生 整个西海岸都停电了
Sir! The entire West Coast has gone down!
不仅仅是能量
It's not just energy.
那个戴立克刚吸收了整个互联网
That Dalek just absorbed the entire internet.
它现在无所不知了
It knows everything!
戴立克的血脉由我延续
The Daleks survive in me!
保险库摄像机被破坏了
The cameras in the vault are down.
我们只有紧急电源 它在吞噬一切
We've only got emergency power. It's eating everything else.
你现在必须杀了它
You should go and kill it now!
所有安保人员立即向笼子进发
All guards to converge on the Metaltron Cage immediately.
他俩是平民 让他们过去
Civilians! Let 'em through!
掩护北墙
Cover the north wall.
红队在周边继续压制火力 蓝队
Reds, maintain suppressing fire along the perimeter. Blues...
告诉他们不要向它射击
Tell them to stop shooting at it.
但它会杀死他们
But it's killing them!
他们可有可无 但那只戴立克是独一无二的
They're dispensable - that Dalek is unique.
我不想让它有丝毫损伤 你们听到了吗
I don't want a scratch on its bodywork! Do you hear me?
你们听到了吗
Do you hear me?
我们在这里 就在地表以下
That's us, right below the surface.
那是笼子 而那是戴立克
That's the Cage, and that's the Dalek.
你们的这个博物馆 有什么外星武器吗
This museum of yours, have you got any alien weapons?
有很多
Lots of them,
但麻烦的是戴立克挡在我们和武器之间
but the trouble is, the Dalek's between us and them.
我们得让它活着
We've got to keep it alive.
我们可以封锁整个保险库 把它困在下面
We could just seal the entire vault, trap it down there.
把所有人都和它困在一起吗
Leaving everyone trapped with it?
洛斯在下面
Rose is down there.
我不会让这种事发生的 你明白吗
I won't let that happen, have you got that?
它得穿过这片区域 那是什么
It has to go through this area. What's that?
武器测试区
Weapons testing.
把枪交给技师 律师 所有人 每个人
Give guns to technicians, lawyers - anyone, everyone.
只有这样你们才有机会杀死它
Only then have you got a chance of killing it.
楼梯 这还差不多
Stairs! That's more like it!
它没有腿 它被挡住了
Hasn't got legs - it's stuck!
它来了 快上去
It's coming! Get up!
强大的外星杀戮机器
Great big alien death machine.
却被小小楼梯打败了
Defeated by a flight of stairs!
现在听我说 我命令你回到笼子里去
Now listen to me. I demand that you return to your Cage.
如果你要协商 那我可以保证
If you want to negotiate, then I can guarantee that
范·斯塔邓先生愿意和你谈话
Mr Van Statten will be willing to talk.
我知道我们囚禁了你 也许这是不对的
I accept that we imprisoned you, and maybe that was wrong,
但已经死了很多人 现在必须结束
but people have died, and that stops - right now.
停止杀人 你明白了吗
The killing stops. Have you got that?
我命令你投降 清楚了吗
I demand that you surrender. Is that clear?
上…升
El-ev-ate.
天呐
Oh, my God.
亚当 带她离开这里
Adam, get her out of here.
跟我们一起走 你阻止不了它
Come with us. You can't stop it.
总得有人试试 你快点走
Someone's got to try. Now get out!
不要回头 快跑
Don't look back, just run!
我还以为你是专家 博士
I thought you were the great expert, Doctor.
如果你这么厉害 为什么不劝服这戴立克呢
If you're so impressive, why not just reason with this Dalek?
它一定愿意协商 它一定有想要的东西
It must be willing to negotiate. It must need something it needs.
万物都有所求
Everything needs something.
最近的城镇是哪里 -盐湖城
What's the nearest town? - Salt Lake City.
人口呢 -一百万
Population? - One million.
全死定了
All dead.
如果戴立克跑出去
If the Dalek gets out,
它会杀死所有生物 这就是它想要的
it'll murder every creature. That's all it needs.
但它为什么要这么做
But why would it do that?
因为它坚信他们都该死
Because it honestly believes they should die.
人类与它不同 而任何不同即为错误
Human beings are different, and anything different is wrong.
它是种族大清洗的终极武器
It's the ultimate in racial cleansing,
而你 范·斯塔邓 你把它放跑了
and you, Van Statten, you let it loose.
戴立克周身有力场环绕
The Dalek's surrounded by a force field.
子弹打到它之前就会熔化
The bullets are melting before they even hit.
但它并非坚不可摧
But it's not indestructible!
如果你集中火力 也许能突破
If you concentrate your fire, you might get through.
瞄准圆顶 头部 眼柄 这些是它的弱点
Aim for the dome - the head, the eyepiece. That's the weak spot.
谢谢 博士 但我觉得
Thank you, Doctor, but I
我知道怎么对抗一个铁皮机器人
think I know how to fight one single tin robot.
就位
Positions!
别开火
Hold your fire!
你们俩 快给我离开这里
You two, get the hell out of there!
它刚才在看我 -对 它想干掉我们
It was looking at me. - Yeah, it wants to slaughter us!
不 它刚才直直地看我
No, but it was looking right at me!
那又怎样 那只是个铁眼睛 它会四处看
So? It's just a sort of metal eye thing, it's looking all around.
我不知道 好像它里面有什么东西
I don't know. It's like there's something inside,
看着我 就像
looking at me, like...
像是它认识我
liike it knows me.
听我命令
On my mark.
开火
Open fire!
我们有图像了
We've got vision!
它想让我们看见
It wants us to see.
撤退 撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
也许是时候改变策略了
Perhaps it's time for a new strategy.
也许我们应该考虑抛弃这个地方
Maybe we should consider abandoning this place.
但是停机坪没有电力供应 先生
Except there's no power to the helipad, sir.
我们出不去
We can't get out.
你说过我们可以封锁保险库吧
You said we could seal the vault?
它是以核战避难所的标准建造的
It was designed to be a bunker in the event of nuclear war.
钢铁隔板
Steel bulkheads...
电力不足 那些隔板太大了
Not enough power! Those bulkheads are massive.
我们有紧急电源 可以把电力引向隔板门
We've got emergency power, we can reroute that to the bulkhead doors.
我们得绕过安全密码 这需要一个电脑天才
We'd to bypass the security codes. That would take a computer genius.
那幸好我就在这里 -你想帮忙吗
Good thing you've got me, then. - You want to help?
我不想死 博士 就这么简单
I don't want to die, Doctor. Simple as that.
而且没人比我更了解这里的软件 -先生
And nobody knows this software better than me. - Sir... ?
我只和博士说话
I shall speak only to the Doctor.
你会生锈的
You're gonna get rusty.
我提取了洛斯·泰勒的基因
I fed off the DNA of Rose Tyler.
通过推测时间旅者的生物质能使我重生
Extrapolating the biomass of a time-traveller regenerated me.
你还有什么把戏
What's your next trick?
我已经在寻找其他戴立克了
I have been searching for the Daleks.
是的 我看到了
Yeah, I saw.
把互联网都下载了 你找到了什么
Downloading the internet. What did you find?
我扫描了你们的卫星和射电望远镜
I scanned your satellites and radio telescopes.
然后呢 -什么都没有
And? - Nothing.
我该从哪里得到命令呢
Where shall I get my orders now?
你只是个没人指挥的士兵
You're just a soldier without commands.
那我就遵从第一命令
Then I shall follow the Primary Order.
戴立克生来即为了毁灭 为了征服
The Dalek instinct to destroy, to conquer!
为什么 有什么意义
What for? What's the point? !
你还不明白吗 已经不复存在了
Don't you see? It's all gone.
你的族群 你们坚持的一切
Everything you were, everything you stood for.
那我该做什么呢
Then what should I do?
好吧
All right, then.
如果你想要命令 执行这个吧
If you want orders, follow this one.
自我了断
Kill yourself.
戴立克必须活着
The Daleks must survive!
戴立克一族已经失败了
The Daleks have failed!
为什么你不干脆让戴立克彻底灭绝呢
Why don't you finish the job and make the Daleks extinct?
还宇宙一个清净之地 为什么你不去死呢
Rid the universe of your filth! Why don't you just DIE? !
你会是一个优秀的戴立克
You would make a good Dalek.
封锁保险库
Seal the vaults.
我可以从地面防守系统中偷取电力
I can leech power off the ground defences,
转移到隔板上
feed it to the bulkheads.
我好久没有这么努力工作了
It's years since I had to work this fast!
你很享受吗 -博士 她还在下面
Are you enjoying this?! - Doctor. She's still down there.
现在可不是打电话的好时候
This isn't the best time!
你在哪里 -49层
Where are you? - Level 49.
你不能停下
You've got to keep moving.
保险库正在从46层开始封锁
The vault is being sealed off up at level 46.
你可以让它们不要关吗
Can't you stop them closing?
就是我正在关闭它们
I'm the one who's closing them.
我等不了了 我也帮不了你
I can't wait, and I can't help you.
看在上帝的份上 快跑
Now for God's sake, run!
搞定 电力被运到隔板上了
Done it! Power to the bulkheads.
戴立克现在就在他们后面
The Dalek's right behind them.
我们快到了 等我们几秒钟
We're nearly there, give us two seconds!
博士 供电无法维持了 系统正在崩溃
Doctor, I can't sustain the power. The whole system is failing.
博士 你必须关闭隔板了
Doctor, you've got to close the bulkheads.
对不起
I'm sorry.
快点
Come on!
保险库被封闭了
The vault is sealed.
洛斯 你在哪 洛斯 你过去了吗
Rose! Where are you? Rose, did you make it?
抱歉 我慢了一步
Sorry. I was a bit slow.
再见了 博士
See you, then, Doctor.
这不是你的错
It wasn't your fault.
你要记住 这不是你的错
Remember that, OK? It wasn't your fault.
你知道吗
And d'you know what?
就算你不这么做最后也难逃一死
I wouldn't have missed it for the world.
消灭
Exterminate!
它杀了她 -抱歉
It killed her. - I'm sorry.
我说过我会保护她的
I said I'd protect her.
她因为我才来到这里 而你在这里说抱歉
She was here because of me, and you're sorry? !
我在囚室里就能干掉那个戴立克
I could have killed that Dalek in its cell,
但是你阻止了我
but you stopped me.
它是我收藏中的珍品
It was the prize of my collection!
你的收藏 这值得吗
Your collection? ! Was it worth it?
值得让这些人去死 让洛斯被杀
Worth all those men's deaths? Worth Rose?
让我告诉你点事儿 范·斯塔邓
Let me tell you something, Van Statten.
人类进入宇宙进行探索
Mankind goes into space to explore,
成为更广阔空间的一部分
to be part of something greater...
没错 我只是想要触摸星星
Exactly! I wanted to touch the stars.
你只想把星辰从空中拽下
You just want to drag the stars down and
把它们埋藏在无数沙尘中
stick them underground underneath tons of sand and dirt,
并且给它们贴上标签
and label them.
你和星星的距离比谁都远
You're about as far from the stars as you can get.
你还害她一起陪葬
And you took her down with you.
她只有19岁
She was 19 years old.
动手吧 杀了我
Go on then, kill me.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this? !
我有武器 我要杀戮
I am armed. I will kill.
这是我生存的意义
It is my purpose.
他们死了都是因为你
They're all dead because of you!
他们死了都是因为我们
They are dead because of US!
现在呢
And now what?
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?
我能感受到你的恐惧
I feel your fear.
不然还有什么
What d'you expect?
戴立克没有恐惧 不能有恐惧
Daleks do not fear. Must not fear!
你给了我生命
You gave me life.
你还给了我什么
What else have you given me?
我被污染了
I am contaminated.
你自己跑得快 丢下洛斯一个人
You were quick on your feet, leaving Rose behind.
关上门的不是我
I'm not the one who sealed the vault!
开门 不然我就杀了洛斯·泰勒
Open the bulkhead or Rose Tyler dies.
你还活着 -甩不掉我的
You're alive! - Can't get rid of me.
我以为你死了 -开门
I thought you were dead. - Open the bulkhead!
别开 -如果救不了你爱的女人
Don't do it! - What use are emotions,
那你的情感有什么用
if you will not save the woman you love?
我已经害死了她一次
I killed her once.
我不能再那样做了
I can't do it again.
我们现在怎么办
What do we do now?
你个大善人 我们现在怎么办
You bleeding heart, what the hell do we do?
在它过来的时候杀了它 -枪没有用
Kill it when it gets here. - The guns are useless,
外星武器都在库里 -只有登记过的
and the alien weapons are in the vault. - Only the catalogued ones.
坏的
Broken.
吹风机
Hairdryer.
范·斯塔邓先生会
Mr Van Statten tends to
抹除员工的记忆然后开除
dispose of his staff and wipe their memory.
我留着这些以防万一
I kept this in case I
哪天我需要杀出重围
needed to fight my way out.
就你还打打杀杀 我倒想见识见识
What, you in a fight? I'd like to see that.
我能行 -你要怎么做
I could do! - What you gonna do,
把考试成绩单扔到他们脸上 这个好
throw your A Levels at 'em? ...Oh, yes!
准备进攻
Lock and load!
求求你 不要杀他们 你没有杀我
I'm begging you, don't kill them. You didn't kill me.
为什么没有 为什么你还活着
But why not? Why are you alive?
我的功能就是杀戮 我是什么
My function is to kill. What am I?
我是什么
What am I? !
不许动 什么也别做
Don't move! Don't do anything!
它开始质疑自己了
It's beginning to question itself.
范·斯塔邓
Van Statten.
你为什么折磨我
You tortured me. Why?
我只是希望帮助你
I wanted to help you, I just.
我也不知道 我只是想帮忙
I don't know, I was trying to help.
我以为只要能跟你说上话 就能修好你
I thought if we could get through to you, could mend you...
我想帮你 对不起
I wanted you better. I'm sorry.
万分抱歉 我发誓我只是想让你说话
I'm so sorry. I swear, I just wanted you to talk!
那么现在听我说
Then hear me talk now.
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
停下 别杀他 你不需要继续杀人了
Don't do it! Don't kill him! You don't have to do this any more.
你心中肯定还有别的事
There must be something else,
不只是杀戮 你心中还有什么
not just killing. What else is there?
你想要什么
What do you want? !
我想要
I want...
自由
freedom.
你出来了 你成功了
You're out. You made it.
我还以为再也感受不到阳光的温暖
I never thought I'd feel the sunlight again.
那是什么感觉
How does it... feel?
让开
Get out of the way!
洛斯 快点让开
Rose, get out of the way, now!
不 我不会让你这么做的
No! Cos I won't let you do this.
那个东西杀死了成百上千的人
That thing killed hundreds of people.
现在拿枪对着我的不是它
It's not the one pointing the gun at me.
我必须这么做 我必须结束这一切
I've got to do this. I've got to end it.
戴立克毁灭了我的家园 我的族人
The Daleks destroyed my home, my people.
我什么都没有了
I've got nothing left.
好好看它
Look at it.
它在做什么
What's it doing?
阳光 它只是想要阳光
It's the sunlight. That's all it wants.
不可能
But it can't...
它没有杀范·斯塔邓 也没有杀我
It couldn't kill van Statten, it couldn't kill me.
它在改变 而你呢 博士
It's changing. And what about you, Doctor?
你现在变成了什么
What the hell are you changing into?
我不能…
I couldn't...
我不是…
I wasn't...
洛斯
Oh, Rose.
他们都死了
They're all dead.
为什么我们还活着
Why do we survive?
我不知道
I don't know.
我是最后一个戴立克
I am the last of the Daleks.
你连戴立克都不是了
You're not even that.
洛斯不仅仅让你重生了
Rose did more than regenerate you.
你吸收了她的DNA
You've absorbed her DNA.
你正在发生变异
You're mutating.
变成什么
Into what?
某种新东西
Something new.
对不起
I'm sorry.
那不是更好吗
Isn't that better?
对戴立克来说不是
Not for a Dalek.
我能感受到
I can... feel
千思万绪
so many ideas.
还有黑暗
So much darkness.
洛斯 给我下令
Rose. Give me orders.
下令让我死
Order me to die.
我不能
I can't do that.
这不是活着
This is not life.
这是病态
This is sickness.
我不会变成你那样
I shall not be like you!
令我自毁
Order my destruction!
服从
Obey!
服从 服从
Obey! Obey!
动手吧
Do it.
你害怕吗 洛斯·泰勒
Are you frightened, Rose Tyler?
害怕
Yeah.
我也是
So am I.
消灭
Exterminate.
你要干嘛 -200人死亡
What the hell are you doing? - 200 personnel dead,
都是因为你 先生
and all because of you, sir.
带走 清除记忆
Take him away, wipe his memory
随便丢在什么地方的路边
and leave him by the road someplace.
你不能这么对我 我是亨利·范·斯塔邓
You can't do this to me! I am Henry van Statten!
到了今天晚上
By tonight,
亨利·范·斯塔邓就是一个无家可归的瘾君子
Henry Van Statten will be a homeless, brainless junkie,
流落在这些街头
living on the streets of
圣地亚哥 西雅图 萨克拉门托
San Diego, Seattle, Sacramento
总之是某个S打头的城市街头
some place beginning with S.
家乡的一块碎片 聊胜于无
Little piece of home. Better than nothing.
这就是最后的结局吗 时间大战
Is that the end of it? The Time War.
我是唯一生还的人
I'm the only one left.
我赢了 听起来怎么样
I win. How about that?
有戴立克幸存下来
The Dalek survived.
也许你的一些族人还活着 -我会知道的
Maybe some of your people did too. - I'd know.
会有感觉的
In here.
感觉没有人还活着
Feels like there's no-one.
那还好我哪儿也不去
Well, then. Good thing I'm not going anywhere.
我们最好赶快走 范·斯塔邓不见了
We'd better get out. Van Statten's disappeared.
他们要关闭这里
They're closing down the base.
戈达德说要在这里灌满水泥
Goddard says they're gonna fill it with cement,
就当这里从未存在过 -终于
like it never existed! - About time.
我得回家了 -那最好快点
I'll have to go back home. - Better hurry up, then.
下一趟飞往伦敦希斯罗机场的航班是三点整
Next flight to Heathrow leaves at 1500 hours.
亚当说他这辈子一直梦想着去看看群星
Adam said that all his life, he wanted to see the stars.
告诉他出门自己看
Tell him to go and stand outside, then.
他孤身一人 博士
He's all on his own, Doctor.
他刚才也帮忙了 -他刚丢下你一个人
And he did help. - He left you there!
你也是 -你们在说什么 我们该走了
So did you. - What are you talking about? ! We've got to leave!
而且 他长得有点帅
Plus, he's a bit pretty.
我没注意 -后果自负
I hadn't noticed. - On your own head...
你们在干嘛 她说的可是水泥
What are you doing? She said cement.
她可不是开玩笑 我们会被封在这里的
She wasn't joking - we're gonna get sealed in!
博士
Doctor?
你们站在盒子里干嘛
What are you doing standing inside a box?
洛斯
Rose?
下集预告
富饶的第四人类帝国
The fourth great and bountiful human empire.
地球鼎盛时期
Planet Earth at its height.
客隆芝士堡 客隆薯芋茄堡
Kronkburger with cheese, kronkburger with pajatos.
不对劲
Something's wrong.
我的手表一定是坏了
My watch must be wrong.
这就是炫耀的结果
That's what comes with showing off.
你的历史没你想的那么好
Your history's not as good as you thought.
我的历史没问题 -显然不是
My history's perfect. - Well, obviously not.
我能尝出来 -安全连接
I can taste it. - Engage safety.
下面某个人不属于这里
'Someone down there shouldn't be here.'
你是谁
Who are you?
我是编辑
I'm the editor.
发生了什么 -启动
What's happening? - And spike.